Festival Accompanying Chapter
Part Eleven
End
saa, wasuremashou sono mirai ga
Come, let us forget about the future...
Planning
Takeshi Oikawa
Akihiro Kawamura
Akihiro Yuasa
Original Work ・ Original Story/Supervision
Ryukishi07/07th Expansion
"Higurashi no Naku Koro ni"
"Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kai"
mata chinurarete yuku nante
...ending up stained in blood again.
Series Composition
Toshifumi Kawase
Character Design
Overall Animation Supervisor
Kyuuta Sakai
Art Director
Chikako Shibata
Color Design
Shinji Matsumoto
namanurui kaze toguro wo maitara
If the soft wind coils up...
Camera Director
Masayuki Kawaguchi
Editing
Masahiro Matsumura
Music
Kenji Kawai
Sound Director
Hozumi Gouda
sore ga tabun aizu
...that is probably a sign.
nukedashitette
Break free.
Opening Theme
"Naraku no Hana"
(Flower in Hell)
Vocals
Lyrics
Composition
Arrangement
Eiko Shimamiya
Tomoyuki Nakazawa
Takeshi Ozaki
kanashisugiru unmei kara
From your heart-wrenching fate.
Music Producer
Music Production
Akira Yoshikawa
Frontier Works
anata wa naraku no hana ja nai
You are not a flower in hell.
Producers
Mika Nomura
Hiroyuki Oomori
Takeshi Okamura
sonna basho de sakanaide
Don't blossom in such a place.
Animation Producer
Animation Production
Kouji Iijima
Studio Deen
sakanaide
Don't blossom there.
karametorarete ikanaide
Don't get entangled.
oto mo naku tobikau toki no kakera
Fragments of time flutter about without a sound.
Kai
Hi
ni
ra
ku
Koro
gu
no
shi
Na
Kai
Production
Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kai Production Committee
Director
Chiaki Kon
（赤坂(あかさか)）ううっ！
Prepare to fire!
（隊員）発射用意！
What!?
（隊員）何!?　スナイパー！
（隊員）ううっ ううっ
Sniper!
銃声はなかった
We didn't hear a gunshot!
距離 400以上だ！
（隊員）ううっ
He's over four hundred meters away!
Forget about that!
そんなことは どうでもいい
撃て！　撃て 撃て！
Fire!
Fire! Fire!
What!?
（隊員）何!?
（隊員たち）うわあ！
（詩音(しおん)）そりゃそうです
That was to be expected.
（詩音）
園崎(そのざき)家 御用達の防弾仕様ですから
The car is armored with the Sonozaki family's preferred bulletproof plating, after all!
Follow them!
（隊員）追撃しろ！
（エンジン音）
Damn.
くそっ なんて奴らだ！
These guys are insane!
So Major Takano was the mastermind after all?
（男性）では やはり首謀者は
鷹野(たかの)三佐だったのですか
Yes. Regrettably.
（富竹(とみたけ)）ええ 残念ながら
入江(いりえ)機関の早急な制圧を！
Take immediate control over the Irie Institution.
They have already fired their weapons many times above ground.
彼らは すでに
地上での発砲を繰り返しており―
At this rate, it is only a matter of time before the villagers find out.
このままでは 村人に発覚するのも
時間の問題です
I strongly request for the immediate dispatchment of the Banken.
番犬の緊急出動を強く要請します
（男性）了解
Roger.
Did you get through to them?
（赤坂）話はつきましたか？
（富竹）ええ
Yes.
番犬部隊というのは
どの程度 強いのですか？
How strong is this Banken unit, really?
If we consider the Yamainu to be a general-purpose covert operations unit...
山狗(やまいぬ)が機密保持のための
多目的部隊だとしたら―
番犬は戦闘のために特化した
精鋭部隊です
...then the Banken are an elite force specializing in combat.
Their armament and manpower is far and beyond that of the Yamainu.
装備も人材も
山狗とは比べものになりません
What will you do now...
これからどうしますか？　富竹さん
...Tomitake-san?
I'm...
私 雛見沢(ひなみざわ)へ戻ろうと思ってます
...thinking of going back to Hinamizawa.
まだ みんな戦ってる
Everyone is still fighting.
ああ… いいのかい？
一度は くぐり抜けた死線だよ？
Are you sure?
It's a danger zone we just managed to barely escape from.
Rika-chan is waiting.
梨花(りか)ちゃんが待ってる
I haven't fulfilled my promise yet.
私は まだ約束を果たしていない
なら 戻ろう
僕もやり残したことがある
Then let's go back.
I have unfinished business to attend to as well.
ん？　やり残したこと？
Unfinished business?
This is Okonogi!
（小此木(おこのぎ)）
こちら小此木　応答せよ！
Respond!
Enough!
もういい　ここまでだ！
（隊員）はあ…
Stop!
Everyone, return to your vehicles at the base of the mountain and await further orders.
お前たちは
ふもとの車両に戻り待機してろ
（隊員）はあ 了解しました
Roger that.
What are you doing!?
（鷹野）何をしてるの！
奴らは目の前なのよ！
They're right in front of us!
Okonogi!
小此木！　私に逆らう気なの？
Are you disobeying me!?
Far from it.
（小此木）とんでもない
（鷹野）あっ！
There she is!
いたわ 梨花よ！
小此木 捕らえなさい！
It's Rika!
Okonogi!
Seize her!
何してるの！　早く捕まえなさい！
What are you waiting for!?
Hurry up and capture her!
ちいと黙っとれや！
（鷹野）ハッ
Just shut up for a moment!
I am Okonogi of the Yamainu!
山狗の小此木だ
お前らのリーダーに敬意を表する
Allow me to express my respect for your leader!
Please tell me your name!
名前を聞かせてくれ！
Club Leader...
...Mion Sonozaki.
You have won this fight.
（小此木）
この戦いはお前らの勝ちだ！
（鷹野）小此木？
（小此木）富竹は封鎖線を突破
Okonogi...!?
Tomitake has breached our barricade line...
...so it is only a matter of time for a unit to put us down to arrive.
鎮圧部隊がやってくるのも
時間の問題だ
小此木！　あっ
Okonogi!
大したもんだよ あんた
You really are quite something.
With proper training, you could make it big in SAS, Delta Force, or you name it.
鍛えようによっちゃ
サツでもデルタフォースでも―
どこでも
最高の人材になれるだろうぜえ
サツ？　デルタフォース？
くっだらないねえ
SAS?
Delta Force?
How worthless!
There is only one thing I want to do.
あたしがやりたいのは たった１つ
And that is to be the leader of our club at the Hinamizawa Branch School!
雛見沢分校の我が部の部長だけさ！
Magician of words, Keiichi Maebara.
口先の魔術師 前原(まえばら)圭一(けいいち)
かぁいいモードの竜宮(りゅうぐう)レナ
Rena Ryuuguu and her Take-it-home Mode.
Trap specialist Satoko.
トラップ使いの沙都子(さとこ)に
タヌキの梨花ちゃん！
Sly fox Rika-chan.
And our promising newbie.
そして期待の新人 古手(ふるで)羽入(はにゅう)！
Hanyuu Furude.
With such an awesome bunch, we won't be bored wherever we go!
これだけそろってりゃ
世界のどこだろうと退屈しないね！
Okonogi!
小此木！　何やってるの！
What are you doing!?
その女は敵のリーダーよ
倒しなさい！
That woman is the enemy leader!
Bring her down!
まあ 勝負はついてるんだが
お姫様の命令なんでなあ
Well, even though this battle is already over...
...it's the princess' orders.
（男性）
入江機関の全職員に告ぐ
Attention all members of the Irie Institution.
As of today at 1230 hours, the authority of the Irie Institution has been frozen.
本日１２３０(ひとふささんまる)に
入江機関の全権限は凍結された
ただちに武装解除し 投降せよ
Disarm yourselves and surrender immediately.
In case of resistance, we will not hesitate to apprehend you with force.
これに応じない場合―
厳正に対処することを
ここに通告する
Not yet!
まだよ！
まだ終わってないわ！
It's not over yet!
Is it...
（沙都子）これで終わりですの？
...over now?
I don't know.
（梨花）分かりませんのです
初めてのことなので
This has never happened before.
Rika-chan!
（赤坂）梨花ちゃーん！
（梨花）ハッ
ハア　無事でよかった
I'm so glad you're safe!
Akasaka...
赤坂… 赤坂！
Akasaka!
（赤坂）おっ おお アハッ
Akasaka, Akasaka!
赤坂 赤坂
無事でよかったのです！
I'm so glad you're safe!
It appears they have already taken control of the clinic, under Dr. Irie's guidance.
入江先生の誘導で 診療所も
すでに彼らが制圧したそうだよ
So Manager is okay, too!
（レナ）監督も無事だったんだね
よかった
（圭一）うん
Thank goodness.
The Yamainu members are surrendering one after another.
（赤坂）山狗の隊員たちも
続々と投降に応じてる
It seems they have taken charge of the boy that was with them, too.
一緒にいた少年も
彼らに保護されたそうだよ
んっ？　少年？
Boy?
Satoko...
沙都子　本当によかったのです
I'm so glad!
うーん…
（圭一）あれっ 羽入は？
Hm?
Where's Hanyuu?
（レナ）さっきまでいたよね
She was here just now, wasn't she?
羽入…
Hanyuu...
What is this about!?
（鷹野）どういうことなの!?
状況がさっぱり分からないわよ！
I have no idea what's going on!
We're at a stalemate.
（小此木）
手詰まりってやつですんで
番犬が到着したんですわ
The Banken have arrived.
Banken?
番犬？　どうして応戦しないの！
Why don't you fight back!?
フッ ご冗談を
山狗はしょせん防諜(ぼうちょう)部隊です
You must be joking...
The Yamainu are just a counter-intelligence unit.
The Banken, on the other hand, are a real combat unit.
対して番犬は
ほんまもんの戦闘部隊ですわ
はなから勝ち目なんざありませんよ
We don't have a snowball's chance in hell to win.
だ… 大体
どうして番犬が来るのよ
Why did the Banken come in the first place!?
First Lieutenant Tomitake escaped the clinic...
（小此木）
富竹二尉が診療所から逃走
東京に連絡したんですわ
...and contacted Tokyo.
ううっ！　そんなの聞いてないわ！
I didn't hear about this!
いつよ!?
どうなってるの 小此木！
When did this happen!?
What's going on, Okonogi!?
（隊員）
こちら指揮車　聞こえますか？
Command vehicle here.
Can you hear me?
小此木だ
Okonogi here.
Captain!
（隊員）
隊長 郭公(かっこう)より最終連絡です
This is Cuckoo's final message.
"Initiate cleanup operations."
“後片づけを実行せよ”
Roger that.
（小此木）了解した
（隊員）
なお 指揮車を番犬が包囲中です
投降を勧告していますが…
Furthermore, the command vehicle is under siege by the Banken.
Requesting permission to surrender.
（小此木）了解　投降を許可する
（鷹野）んっ！
Got it.
Permission granted.
（小此木）武装解除して
今は番犬の指示に従え
Disarm yourselves and obey the Banken's orders hereafter.
Command vehicle, roger.
（隊員）指揮車 了解
Not yet!
まだよ！　何とか
東京の野村(のむら)さんと連絡を取るのよ！
I'm going to contact Nomura-san in Tokyo somehow!
梨花は生きていたのよ！
Rika was alive!
終末作戦の実行は可能だわ！
It is still possible to execute Operation Termination!
（小此木）三佐
このゲームはうちらの負けです
Major.
We have lost the game.
Being poor losers isn't going to do either of us any good.
（小此木）往生際の悪さは
互いの得になりませんねえ
何を言うの？　小此木
What are you talking about...
...Okonogi?
Your role is already over.
あんたの役割は もうおしまいです
W-What are you saying...?
な… 何よ それ…
私の役割って…
My role...?
あっ 何するのよ！
これは おじいちゃんの大事な…
What are you doing!?
These are Grandpa's precious...
そんな研究
はなっから どうでもええんですわ
Nobody gave a damn about that research from the start.
何言ってるの!?
What are you talking about!?
The possibilities of humanity's future are documented in here...!
ここには人類の…
未来の可能性が…
（小此木）
そんなこと誰も信じとらんですよ
Nobody believes that crap.
Whether what is written is true or false...
ましてや ほんとかウソかなんて
東京には何の関係もないことですわ
...is not of any interest at all to Tokyo.
What do you mean?
（鷹野）どういうこと？
大事なのは
それが東京の連中にとって―
What's important is whether or not the people in Tokyo...
政治的アクションに使えるかどうか
...can reap political benefits out of it.
Fortunately for you...
幸いなことに―
...the client in Tokyo still has a role for you they expect you to fulfill.
東京のクライアントが 三佐にまだ
期待している役割があるんですわ
What's this...?
何よ これ
There is only one bullet inside.
１発だけ入ってます
自決用ってやつですな
Use it to resign yourself.
Major...
三佐 そいつで自分の頭
ぶち抜いてくれませんか？
...would you kindly put a bullet through your head with that?
（鷹野）ハッ
（小此木）よくあるやつですわ
This is not at all uncommon.
トカゲのしっぽですよ
敗軍の将の責任ってやつですわ
The lizard sometimes has to shed its tail.
You could call it the responsibility of the defeated commander.
N-No way...
そ… そんな
それでクライアントも―
With that, the client intends to cleanly wrap everything up by putting the blame for all that's happened on you.
三佐が１人であることないこと
やってくれたってことで―
丸く終わらせるつもりですわ
すでに東京は
その準備に入ってますんで
Tokyo is already making arrangements for this.
Don't...
バ… バカなこと言わないで！
Don't be ridiculous!
I couldn't possibly...
そんなこと… できるわけ…
...do this...!
“投降を説得するも
かたくなに拒否”
After trying to persuade you to surrender, you stubbornly resisted.
It escalated into a gunfight, and I had to kill you out of necessity.
“銃撃戦になり やむなく射殺”
って筋書きのほうですか
That's how the scenario has been drawn up.
（鷹野）筋書き？　何よ それ！
誰が考えたのよ！
Scenario!?
What are you talking about?
Who came up with that!?
The one you have been depending on.
あんたが頼りにしてた
東京の野村さんですよ
Nomura-san from Tokyo.
えっ そ… そんな
あっ ああ…
It...
It can't be...
You are so helpless.
（小此木）あんたも哀れだなあ
ピエロは
退場も踊りながらするもんです
A pierrot dances his way off the stage.
Do you understand, Major?
分かりますか？　三佐
I'm being way too soft on her...
俺も 甘(あめ)えよなあ
Higurashi no Naku Koro ni
Kai
Retriever Leader to all.
（番犬隊長）
レトリバー
リーダーよりオール
Fugitive Major Takano is still on the run.
重要手配犯の鷹野三佐が
現在逃走中
鷹野三佐は現在武装している模様
注意されたし！
Major Takano appears to be armed.
Act with caution.
Cut her off by patrolling around the point she escaped from.
逃走地点を中心に
パトローリングで封殺せよ！
うっ うっ… イヤだ　うっ…
No...
I don't want to die...
死にたくない　死にたくないよお
I don't want to die!
Child of man.
人の子よ
お前は人の世に何を求めたのか
What did you seek from this world?
I just...
（鷹野）私は… 私はただ…
I just wanted to be told...
..."It's okay to live."
“生きていいよ”って…
"It's okay to be alive, as an individual."
“人として―”
“生きていていいよ”って―
I just wanted someone to acknowledge me!
誰かに
認めてもらいたかっただけなのに
And yet...
なのに なんでこんな…
Why did it come to this...
うっ…
これが私の罪に対する報いなのね
This is retribution for my sins, isn't it?
I am not human.
（羽入）我は人にあらず
I am one who stands above man.
人を超える存在にして
人の罪を許す存在
An existence that forgives man's sins.
Sins of man cannot be forgiven by man.
人の罪は人には許せぬ
我こそが人を許そう
I, however, can forgive man.
I can forgive thee.
そなたを許そう
Impossible.
無理よ　もう無理
It's too late.
Hanyuu!
（梨花）羽入！
（鷹野）あっ
Takano!?
（梨花）鷹野
（圭一たち）あっ
（鷹野）フフフッ　最後の最後で
一矢報いることはできそうねえ
Looks like I'll be able to go out with a bang at the very, very end.
Mion-chan!
魅音ちゃん
If you don't want me to shoot your friends, step forward!
お友達を撃たれたくなかったら
一歩前に出なさあい
あっ 魅ぃちゃん
Mii-chan!
Everything is messed up because of you.
あなたのおかげで めちゃくちゃよ
I won't be forgiven, anyway.
どうせ私は許されない
But it is just too frustrating to go out like this.
でも このままでは
あまりに悔しいわ
So...
だから ねっ？
せめてお返しをさせて！
...you know?
At least let me pay you back some!
げっ やけくそかよ！
Is she desperate!?
そのとおりよ！
弾も１発しかないもの
Yes I am!
I only have one bullet!
But as long as I have one...
でも １発あれば… ねえ？
...right?
んっ 鷹野
Takano...
Nobody move, now.
誰も動いちゃダメよお
If you rush me, I don't know who I'll end up hitting!
焦って撃ったら 誰に当たるか
分かんなくなっちゃうからねえ
Everyone.
みんな あたしの後ろに隠れてて
Hide behind my back.
ンフフッ 勇敢ねえ
How gallant of you.
You're sacrificing yourself for your friends by taking the bullet?
誰かを撃たれるくらいなら
自分が撃たれようという自己犠牲？
（魅音）ああ 撃ちなよ
その代わり絶対にあたしに当てな！
Yeah.
Go ahead and shoot.
But you'd better hit me.
Just you try and hit one of my friends!
あたし以外の仲間に当ててみろ！
I'll put you through a fate worse than death!
あんたを
死ぬよりつらい目に遭わせてやる！
How scary!
怖い　ンフフッ
Mion-san!
魅音さん
Nobody move.
（魅音）みんな動くんじゃないよ
あたしは部長さ
I'm the club leader.
If I can protect you all behind my back, then there's nothing that would make me happier.
みんなを背中に守れるなら
こんなにうれしいことはないね！
Mii...
魅ぃ
You guys play a lot of games, don't you?
あなたたち
よくゲームをするわよねえ
Do you play the card game Old Maid?
トランプのババ抜きはやる？
We sure don't.
やらないね
うちらはジジ抜きばっかだよ！
We just play Old Geezer.
（鷹野）フッ 同じようなルールよ
The rules are about the same.
The sin in this world is just like Old Maid.
人の世の罪はババ抜きと同じ
Everyone pushes the one old maid onto one another.
誰もが１枚のババを
互いに押しつけ合う
It is not a game you seek to win...
それは
勝ちを求めるゲームではなく―
...but one in which you seek to make someone the loser. The sacrifice.
１人の敗者という
いけにえを求めるゲーム
I have drawn the old maid.
私は そのババを引いた
That is why I will have my revenge for that by shooting you!
だから その腹いせに
あなたを撃つの！
Courageous Mion.
（羽入）勇敢なる魅音
あなたの勇気はそれで十分です
You have shown enough bravery for now.
If the old maid of this world...
人の世のババ抜きが―
...has to be unconditionally pushed onto one person...
必ず誰かに押しつけられなければ
ならないのならば―
...then it is my role to accept it.
それを引き受けるのが私の役目
Hanyuu!
羽入 あんた何を！
What are you saying!?
Rika.
（羽入）梨花
この世界はすごく楽しかったです
I had a lot of fun in this world.
I am so glad I got to be a part of the club.
ボクも部活メンバーに加われて
よかったです
Not by simply watching...
見てるだけじゃなく―
...but by being able to spend time together, I was truly happy.
一緒に過ごせた時間は
本当に幸せだった
Thank you.
ありがとう　もう十分に楽しんだ
I've enjoyed myself more than plenty.
Come!
さあ撃て 人の子よ！
Shoot, child of man!
Release the unwashable sins of this world upon me!
人の世の
押しつけずには済まぬ罪を放て！
I will accept them all!
それを受け止めてやる
Fine.
（鷹野）分かった　分かったわ
Fine!
死ねえ！
（銃声）
Die!
フッ フフッ 外しやがった！
（レナ）ハッ！
She missed!
How...
（鷹野）こ… この私が
この距離で外すなんて
How could I...
...miss from this range...?
Takano and Hanyuu, were you listening to what Mion said?
（梨花）鷹野も羽入も
魅音の話を聞いていたの？
We don't play Old Maid.
私たちはババ抜きではなく
ジジ抜きしかやらない
Just Old Geezer.
Takano laughed it off as being the same...
それを鷹野は“同じだ”と
笑ったけど 全然違うゲームなのよ
...but it is a completely different game.
だってジジ抜きは
欠けた１枚のカードが足されたら
After all, if one adds the missing card that is taken out in a game of Old Geezer, it becomes a game without losers.
敗者が出ないゲームになる
Rika?
梨花？
（梨花）羽入という
欠けた１枚のカードが加わり―
After adding Hanyuu, our missing card...
...this world became a world free of losers.
この世界は
敗者が出ない世界になった
それをわざわざ１枚抜こうなんて
愚の骨頂
It is the height of folly to purposely take one card out of the game.
This world doesn't need a loser.
この世界に敗者は要らない
That is the answer Rika Furude reached at the end of her thousand year journey in search of a miracle.
それが 古手梨花が
奇跡を求めた―
千年の旅の最後に
たどり着いた答えよ
Major Takano.
（番犬隊員）
鷹野三佐 あなたを逮捕します
You are under arrest.
（鷹野）ハア 私が…
I...
私が全部悪いということになるのね
...am going to be held responsible for everything, aren't I?
（番犬隊員）さあ
（鷹野）ううっ！
Come on.
No!
イヤ！　イヤよ イヤ！
Grandpa's scrapbook!
おじいちゃんのスクラップ
持っていくの！　イヤ イヤー！
I'm bringing it with me!
No, no!
（富竹）待て
（鷹野）あっ… ハッ
Wait.
First Lieutenant Tomitake of the Investigation Bureau.
調査部の富竹二尉だ
彼女は調査部が保護する
The Investigation Bureau will take her into custody.
But...
（番犬隊員）
しかし 司令部から―
...we have received orders from Headquarters to take her to Tokyo immediately.
“ただちに東京へ連行せよ”と
命令を受けています
Don't you notice by looking at her?
（富竹）君たちは
彼女を見て気づかないのか？
Look at her body.
彼女の体を見てみろ
It is covered with scratch marks.
かきむしった痕で
いっぱいじゃないか
We suspect she has contracted a considerably high level of Hinamizawa Syndrome.
雛見沢症候群の
かなり高いレベルの発症が疑われる
Transfer her to the Irie Institution HQ immediately...
（富竹）彼女を直ちに
入江機関本部へ移送し―
...and have her infection level inspected.
発症レベルの検査に入る
Tell Director Irie to prepare treatment measures for Major Takano.
鷹野三佐の
治療態勢を準備させるよう―
入江所長に連絡を！
（番犬隊員）はっ 分かりました
Understood.
Jirou-san...
ジロウさん ジロウさん
Jirou-san.
Today is the day of the Watanagashi festival.
（梨花）
今日は綿流しのお祭りなのです
（子供）
ハハハッ ハハッ… 早く早く
I'm after the bear!
狙うは熊 熊 熊！
（銃声）
The bear!
あーん もう全然ダメだあ
No good at all...
へたくそお
（魅音）んっ！
You suck.
（魅音）てっ てっ てっ！
（圭一）あたっ… あたたたっ
（太鼓の音）
（魅音）ヤバッ！
Oh crap!
梨花の演舞が始まってしまいますわ
Rika's performance is going to start!
Everyone, hurry!
みんな急げ！
（圭一）こらっ 置いてくな！
Hey!
Don't leave me behind!
（大石(おおいし)･入江）ハハハッ
Cast
Keiichi Maebara
Rena Ryuuguu
Mion Sonozaki
Shion Sonozaki
Satoko Houjou
Rika Furude
Hanyuu
Souichiro Hoshi
Mai Nakahara
Satsuki Yukino
Mika Kanai
Yukari Tamura
Yui Horie
Cast
Miyo Takano
Jirou Tomitake
Kuraudo Ooishi
Kyousuke Irie
Mamoru Akasaka
Okonogi
Miyoko Tanashi
Miki Itou
Tohru Ookawa
Chafuurin
Toshihiko Seki
Daisuke Ono
Jurota Kosugi
Fuyuka Ooura
Cast
Radio Voice
Banken Captain
Banken Member
Yamainu
Satoshi Tsuruoka
Kazuyuki Ozawa
Yoshihisa Kawahara
Hiroki Yasumoto
Takuo Kawamura
Nobuyuki Kobushi
Katsuhiro Oota
Gen Nakano
Hello hello!
（詩音）はろろ～ん
（圭一）あっ
ウフッ
Ending Theme
"Taishou a"
(Target a)
Vocals
Lyrics
Composition/
Arrangement
Rika!
（沙都子）梨花！
We're going to be late if you don't wake up soon!
早く起きないと
遅刻してしまいますわよお！
Scenario
Toshifumi Kawase
Storyboards/Episode Direction
Chiaki Kon
Animation Supervisors
Kyuuta Sakai
Minefumi Harada
Animation Supervision Assistance
Chigai Okado
Can't eat anymore...
（羽入）うにゅ うう…
（梨花）ウフッ
（羽入）あっ ウフッ
（梨花･羽入）アハハッ
（沙都子）もう！
Geez!
Animation Production
Studio Deen
Hurry up and put away your futons, you two!
２人とも 早くお布団
片してくださいましい
We can't eat breakfast like this!
ご飯が食べられませんわ！
Okay!
（羽入）はあい！
（梨花）はあい！　なのですよお
[Friday, July 1st]
Production
Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kai Production Committee
© 2007 Ryukishi07/Hinamizawa Three Great Houses
（美代子(みよこ)）遊びに行ってくるねえ！
I'm going out to play!
I-I'm very sorry!
ご… ごめんなさい！
Do you...
（梨花）
あなた 生きたい？　死にたい？
...want to live?
Or do you want to die?
んっ？　生きたい
I want to live...
I see.
（梨花）そう　なら お行きなさい
Then off you go.
Even though your friends aren't home.
どうせ行っても
お友達は留守だけど
Off you go.
お行きなさい
ん… 留守なの？
なら“死にたい”は？
They're not home?
Then what if I want to die?
You will obtain another happy meal flag.
お子様ランチの旗が
もう１本 手に入るわ
えっ？　ああ ずるい！
How mean!
私に内緒で お父さんとお母さん
デパートに行く気だ！
Mom and Dad are going to the department store without telling me!
ずるいずるい！
How mean, how mean!
いいのね？　後悔はしないのね？
Are you sure?
You won't regret it, right?
Why would I regret it?
なんで後悔するの？
Not telling you.
教えてあげないわ　意地悪だから
Because I'm a meanie.
ふうん　ウフッ
大丈夫だよ おねえちゃん
Don't worry, Miss!
No matter what happens, Mom and Dad are with me!
何があっても―
お父さんとお母さんが一緒だもん
ウフッ
（美代子の母）ウフフッ
（美代子）20本そろった
Now I have twenty flags.
God.
神様
これで私 幸せになれるのかな？
Will I be able to live out a happy life now?
（美代子の母）
美代子 歯を磨いてから寝るのよ！
Miyoko!
Brush your teeth before going to sleep!
はあい！
（缶のふたを閉める音）
Okay!